# Bowen Jin

Room 1117, Siebel Center for Computer Science, 201 N. Goodwin Ave, Urbana, IL 61801 Email: bowenj4@illinois.edu | Homepage: https://peterjin.me | Phone: 217-819-1796

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

Natural Language Processing · Graph Mining · Information Retrieval · Recommender System

My research interests lie in modeling unstructured data (e.g., text), structured data (e.g., table, graph) and their intersection. I strive to answer the following questions.

- · What structured knowledge do pretrained language models encode?
- · How to leverage external/internal structure information to better address NLP tasks?
- How to empower structure learning (e.g., graph learning, table learning) with the associated textual semantics signal?

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

2021.08 - Present

Ph.D. Student in Computer Science. Advisor: Prof. Jiawei Han

GPA: 4.0/4.0.

Tsinghua University

2017.09 - 2021.07

B.S. in Electrical Engineering & Statistics. Advisor: Prof. Yong Li

GPA: 3.9/4.0. Outstanding Graduates.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

2021.08 - Present

- Research Assistant. Data Mining Group. Advisor: Prof. Jiawei Han
- · Project: Representation Learning on Text-rich Networks with Pretrained Language Models.

Microsoft Research

2022.05 - 2022.08

- · Research Intern. Information and Data Science Group. Mentors: Dr. Chenyan Xiong and Alec Berntson
- · Project: Dense Retrieval for Heterogeneous Data.

Microsoft Research

2020.09 - 2021.03

- · Research Intern. Social Computing Group. Mentors: Dr. Zheng Liu and Dr. Xing Xie
- · Project: Knowledge-enpowered News Recommendation.

University of California Los Angeles

2020.07 - 2020.09

- Research Assistant. Data Mining Group. Mentor: Prof. Yizhou Sun
- · Project: Kernel-based Graph Pooling for Graph representation Learning.

Tsinghua University

2018.09 - 2020.07

- · Research Assistant. Future Intelligence Lab. Advisor: Prof. Yong Li
- · Project: Recommendation with Graph Neural Networks (First-author paper in SIGIR'20)

University of Michigan

2019.07 - 2019.09

- · Research Assistant. Michigan Institute for Data Science. Advisor: Prof. Ji Zhu
- · Project: Statistical Network Analysis

### SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

Bowen Jin, Yu Zhang, Qi Zhu, and Jiawei Han.

Heterformer: Transformer-based Deep Node Representation Learning on Heterogeneous Text-Rich Networks.

preprint arXiv:2205.10282, 2022

Bowen Jin, Yu Zhang, Yu Meng, and Jiawei Han.

Edgeformers: Graph-Empowered Transformers for Representation Learning on Textual-Edge Networks. The 11th International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR 2023).

Bowen Jin, Chen Gao, Xiangnan He, Depeng Jin, and Yong Li.

Multi-behavior Recommendation with Graph Convolutional Networks.

The 43rd ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR 2020).

#### **AWARDS**

$\boldsymbol{2021}$	Outstanding Graduates (Top $1\%$ in THU)
2021	"Star of Tomorrow" Award, Microsoft Research
2020	China National Scholarship (Top 1% in THU)
2019	China National Scholarship (Top 1% in THU)
2019	Honorable Mention (top 15.35%), Mathematical Contest in Modeling
2018	China National Scholarship (Top 1% in THU)
2017	First Prize, National Olympiad in Mathematics in Provinces

## TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Skills	Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing, Language Modeling, Graph Mining, Weakly Supervised Learning, Unsupervised Learning,
	Information Retrieval
Programming Languages	Python, C/C++, MATLAB, R, Linux, Markdown, Shell, SQL
Machine Learning Packages	PyTorch, Keras, HuggingFace Transformers, Scikit-learn,
3	PyTorch-Geometric, Deep Graph Library
Tools	Bash, LATEX, Git